Hello everyone, welcome to the quick tutorial series of Marlboro's Designer 2025.
In this tutorial, we will introduce the interface layout of Marlboro's Designer.
After opening the software, the top of the interface is the main menu. Here we can select the common tools and functions.
There are two small icons in the upper right corner of the screen. On the left is AI Studio. All the functions related to AI are integrated here for general use.
On the right is the library icon. Here you can download the official default assets or go to the Connect store to download and use the materials in the store.
Next, let's take a look at the interface window composition.
There are two main windows in the middle of the screen. On the left is the 3D window. Here you can open the simulation and adjust the 3D clothing effect.
In the 3D tool bar, there are various 3D windows to help you make better clothing details.
In the lower window, there is a 3D map menu that is used to control the 3D window display content.
Our 3D clothing is made of 2D panels, so we also have a 2D window to adjust all the content related to the panel.
In the 2D tool bar, there are several functions that help you better complete the panel creation and editing.
In addition, there are auxiliary functions such as adding name lines, editing text, etc.
In the lower window, there is also a menu bar for adjusting various display settings.
In addition to these two main windows, right-click on the window title and we can also find the additional main window, the window of the UV editor.
In the UV editor, you can view and arrange the clothing of the UV to cooperate with other 3D software.
In the default situation, you can switch to display the 2D window and the UV editor.
You can separate the main window and customize it for use.
You can also drag the window title to another window and stack them together.
You can also arrange the UV editor window as the third main window and the 3D 2D window together.
Next, let's take a look at the secondary window.
The upper right corner is our object window.
Here you can manage the various materials used in clothing.
For example, material, button, name, Bracelet, Ink, etc.
After choosing a type of object, such as a tree type,
you can check in the property editor below to edit the properties of the object.
In addition, we have some more additional secondary windows.
Right-click on the window name and open these windows.
Next, we will look at the memory page.
You can also arrange, stack, and collect the attached windows at any time.
You can go back to the drop-down menu under the icon to close these attached windows.
Click on the triangle at the bottom of the screen to open the animation editor.
Again, you can record the animation, edit the animation file, and preview the animation effect.
Click on the big X in the upper right corner to close the animation editor.
You can also go to the window menu and open the windows that you need to use.
In the interface layout, you can export the current interface layout for later use.
You may need to return the user interface to the default settings.
You can click on the reset screen layout function in the lower right corner.
In addition, you can choose to display only 3D windows or 2D windows, or display two main windows at the same time.
This is the tutorial for user interface. See you in the next video.